ADITHYA BANDI

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

CONTACT

🔽 adithyb1@umbc.edu

(609) 529-9789

Baltimore, MD

in linkedin.com/in/adithyabandi

github.com/adithya-b

PROFILE

Software Engineer with 3+ years industry experience in building highly scalable products on cloud and academic research experience in Grounded Language Acquisition and Natural Language Processing with an appetite for learning and hunger for problem solving.

EDUCATION

2018

UNIVERSITY OF MARYLAND [BALTIMORE COUNTY]

Master of Computer Science [4.0]

2014

NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY [WARANGAL, IND]

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Java, J2EE, Python, SQL
- Cloud Computing (AWS)
- Redis,MongoDB
- etcd, confd, monit
- Message Queues (Kafka)
- Version Control (Github)
- Docker, Spark, Hive
- Machine Learning
- Numpy, Pandas
- Scikit-Learn, Tensorflow, Keras
- Natural Language Processing
- NLTK. Gensim
- Matplotlib, ggplot

EXPERIENCE

2018 - PRESENT

Research Assistant | Interactive Robotics and Language Lab

- Developed a novel algorithm, which uses Mallet implementation of Latent Dirchlet Allocation Topic Modelling to obtain semantic analysis of entities and then applies SVM Classifier Scikit-Learn implementation to automatically extract most optimal negative samples from positive unlabeled dataset which lead to about 9% increase in performance of downstream classification task helping Robots learn Grounded Language, connecting words, phrases and sentences to its perception of objects and events in the world. The corresponding tests were done on Grid using request level parallelism.
- Worked closely with Baltimore City Officials to implement a Sequence to Sequence Recurrent Neural Network using TensorFlow library for the prediction of the frequency of service requests (for instance street lights out) every month with an objective to optimize Budget Allocation and Resource Utilization resulting in a model with a mean absolute percentage error of 10%.

2016-2018

Software Engineer (R&D) | Amagi Media Labs

- Designed and developed Distributed Real Time component deployed on AWS EC2, Lambda, S3 and CloudFront which solved a crucial business problem of economic viability of product through use of hybrid (server & server-less) architecture leading to first million impressions for a product named Thunderstorm, an OTT Dynamic Ad insertion platform on the cloud.
- Designed and developed a complete server-less component deployed on AWS S3, Lambda, API Gateway using company patented technology to extract and update Ad signatures in real time thereby increasing the revenue by an estimated 10%.
- Played a major role in acquiring the first high profile customer by acting as an interface between the Customer and the product team along with onsite involvement which lead to the first revenue.

2014-2016

Member of Technical Staff | Oracle India Pvt. Ltd.

- Fixed issues related to scheduling component of Business
 Intelligence Publisher deployed both on premise and cloud where I was able to swiftly find root cause through debugging and exploring complex code.
- Developed chef cookbooks for deployment automation on behalf of the team coordinating with teams across the Globe who deploy their product as a part of Oracle Business Intelligence Cloud Services (BICS), which is currently one of the prominent BI offerings in the market.